<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/git/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>git</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 22:05:56 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>git</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/git/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/gitvers_control/gitvers_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 22:05:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/gitvers_control/gitvers_control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:justify&#34;&gt;Version control system: Why is it important? Version control, also known as source code management, is the practice of tracking and managing changes to software code. Version Control Systems (VCS) are software tools that help development teams manage changes to source code over time. In light of the complexity of development environments, they help development teams work faster and more efficiently. SLE allows you to return to any version you want later.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:justify&#34;&gt;The version control software keeps track of all changes made to the code in a special database. If an error is detected, developers can go back and perform a comparison with earlier versions of the code to fix errors, minimizing problems for all team members. In almost all software projects, the source code is a treasure: it is a valuable resource that needs to be protected. For most software development teams, the source code is a repository of invaluable knowledge and understanding of the problem area, which they scrupulously collected and improved. Version control protects the source code from catastrophic failures, from accidental deterioration caused by the human factor, as well as from unforeseen consequences.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
