<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/programming/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Programming</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/programming/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the word &amp;ldquo;Programming&amp;rdquo; can be seen / heard, both in some viral advertisement on a social network, and in a literary or cinematic work. However, what is programming and who are programmers? Without further ado, you can act like a seasoned coder and Google a new word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to numerous definitions, programming is the process of creating computer programs. This definition can be deciphered as follows. Programming is nothing more than explaining to the machine what, in what form and how the user needs to get it. That is, it is a kind of art of translating a person&amp;rsquo;s wishes into the language of a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to make an algorithm and translate it into a programming language. Development gurus often recommend starting program development by answering the question: &amp;ldquo;Is it possible to implement this task programmatically?&amp;rdquo;. For example, even today we cannot force the computer to predict what will happen in a few days. And let this example not be completely correct, because this task is impossible in principle. However, if we narrow down the problem statement to predicting the behavior of some currency on the stock exchange, such a problem is solved with the help of a sufficiently complex algorithm and a large database of experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://example.com/slides/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/slides/programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;programming&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-word-programming&#34;&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Programming&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the word &amp;ldquo;Programming&amp;rdquo; can be seen / heard, both in some viral advertisement on a social network, and in a literary or cinematic work. However, what is programming and who are programmers? Without further ado, you can act like a seasoned coder and Google a new word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-is&#34;&gt;Programming is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the process of creating computer programs. This definition can be deciphered as follows. Programming is nothing more than explaining to the machine what, in what form and how the user needs to get it. That is, it is a kind of art of translating a person&amp;rsquo;s wishes into the language of a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-main-idea&#34;&gt;The main idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to make an algorithm and translate it into a programming language. Development gurus often recommend starting program development by answering the question: &amp;ldquo;Is it possible to implement this task programmatically?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
