<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computer science | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/computer-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>computer science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 22:05:56 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>computer science</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/computer-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to learn English to work in IT.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/it_learn_en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 22:05:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/it_learn_en/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start with vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A specialist from the fields of programming or analytics needs to know a huge amount of specialized vocabulary. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what language you work with, Python or C++ - there are a lot of terms and they need to be studied. The programming languages themselves are also based on English vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you count, the dictionary on the subject of computers and programming contains about 1000-1500 words. For example, the basic general dictionary, which allows you to communicate quite comfortably in English, includes only 4000-5000 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have to study a lot. But if the vocabulary, which is directly related to functions and variables, is remembered in the process of writing by itself, then to communicate with foreign colleagues and read guides, you need to remember the match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is best to study vocabulary in special applications. Here are some of the most effective and easy to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rare words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memriz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hi, Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy Ten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose thematic collections of words and add them to the dictionary. It is worth paying attention to the groups of words Networking, IT slang, English for developers, English for digital technologies, Hacking. Also be sure to choose a collection of words for your specialty. For example, English for system administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 minutes of classes in the app per day — and in 3 months you can learn up to 800 words. This is quite enough to understand technical texts and conversations with specialists of any complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn the construction of complex structures for TK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difficulty of technical English is how to buildnew offers. It has long and sometimes brain-breaking constructions that are difficult to understand without appropriate experience. Take, for example, a short description of one of the Microsoft tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Security Analytics: Using big data, machine learning and Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s unique optics in the Windows ecosystem, enterprise cloud products (such as Office 365) and online resources, behavioral signals are transformed into analytical data, detection and recommended responses to complex threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult for an untrained person to perceive long texts with a dry pitch and complex turns. But it is impossible to convey technical information in any other way. TK for various tasks in it is written in such English, so you understand either in advance or make a large number of edits to your work due to a misunderstanding of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there are a huge number of English courses that help to improve technical English. In most cases, they go 1-2 months and talk about all the nuances of grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constantly work with a live language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning English gives us a skill, not just static knowledge, so like any skill, it needs to be constantly trained. The easiest ways to do this are to listen to podcasts, read thematic forums and professional blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the newer the information in them, the better. The language is constantly changing, and professional slang is especially sensitive to changes. Some phrases, terms and designations become obsolete, new ones appear instead. And it is important to constantly monitor this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, with the help of good podcasts and guides, you can improve not only your English, but also your professional skills. We have put together a small selection that will help with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcasts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio software development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reset programming settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly flossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Is The Life Of Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forums:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack overflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer Forum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming on Reddit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DWB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebDevBlog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cats That Encode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code wall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Wenderlich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TV series and movies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicon Valley (Silicon Valley)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Robot (Mr. Robot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Network (Social Network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Mirror (Black Mirror)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the field of view (Interested person)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TED Talk Presentations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomas Suarez: 12-year-old application developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sergey Brin and Larry Page: how Google was born&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane MacGonigal: the gaming industry can make the world a better place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eric Topol: The wireless future of medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Kelly: How technology is developing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn humor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is humor. Not individual jokes and puns, but the principles of constructing their constructions in English. It may seem that the advice is strange, but it allows you to achieve two goals at once:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are learning the language at a deep level. The very principles of joke formation will show you a huge number of nuances of the language that you didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before. This will improve your understanding of English in general, which will have a positive impact on literacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you know how to make funny jokes on the topic and relieve tension, then you will be a welcome guest in any team. It will be easier for you to find a common language with foreign colleagues and project managers. Such soft skills are very appreciated in the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as a bonus, after a close study of English humor, you will be able to understand a huge number of references and subtle jokes in movies and TV series. Not a profile skill, of course, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be superfluous. The main thing is to study it every day, without breaks and weekends. Just half an hour of classes every day will be many times more effective than five hours once a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are actually very few IT specialists who know English at an excellent level. Most of them are those who work in international companies. But there are also areas in which knowledge of ordinary English and technical is a key skill. For example, Data Science. Most of the information about machine learning and big data is available only in English.
3 tips for web development from the head of the company Evgeny Keenetic Korytov, which help not only to start studying, but also not to quit halfway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose the original&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose the original. Translation is always an interpretation and adaptation to the language you speak, so some of the information may be lost or distorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always watch movies in the original and without subtitles. It is important that it is without subtitles, otherwise you can read the text all the time and not concentrate on the movie. Most often you understand the meaning from the context of what is said. You have visual confirmation — from the plot and the behavior of the characters, you can guess what they were talking about. At first it was difficult, sometimes nothing is clear and I wanted to give up everything. But, just as children learn to speak in the environment of the language, so you eventually begin to understand. Hence the second principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surround yourself with what you want to do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is not only a psychological trick when you put dumbbells on the aisle, so that after passing by you can remember and go to physical education. I have set up all my phones, laptops and other equipment in English, I use Google in English to search the Internet. Email-subscription in English, podcasts, etc. When you make a mistake a couple of times with parking due to a misunderstanding of the language, you will immediately learn all the words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in order not to break down at some point of complete misunderstanding, I use assistants. In addition to Google Translate, I have set up a quick search for words from the context menu of the mouse. Apple has the ability to set up different dictionaries in all its devices to search for the meaning of a word anywhere. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are in a Telegram or on a website, or reading mail in PDF format. An alternative may be an extension to the browser so that incomprehensible words are translated into your native language when highlighted. It can also be customized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I went to study with an English-speaking teacher. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult, but it&amp;rsquo;s also motivating. There are also conversational clubs. Even if you can&amp;rsquo;t speak them right away because of the embarrassment of your level, you will eventually get involved. Conversational clubs of interest come in best of all. And this is the third principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find an interest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched for a long time, but then I realized that I was really interested in what my idols were singing and talking about. Queen, AC/DC, Led Zeppelin, the original voice of actors in movies — especially when they sing. Well, or listen to Uncle Bob - Uncle Bob - Robert Martin. All this is like watching the source code of a library that you use in your work — the original, and that&amp;rsquo;s the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/nauch_prog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 22:05:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/nauch_prog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a highly oriented programming style for scientific calculations. It is distinguished from other types of programming by the extreme correctness and stability of the final product, the strict separation of the scientific and interface parts, the individuality of algorithms, as well as the predominance of efficiency over versatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is at the heart of any modern global research. All advanced technologies — from quantum computers to space programs — would be impossible without specialists in the field of scientific programming, able to provide scientists with a reliable and accurate tool for making discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of branches of science directly depend on the level of development of scientific programming. So, unmanned vehicles, &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; control systems for urban and agricultural management, stock exchanges are waiting for their execution; robotics, genetic engineering, artificial intelligence that surpasses human capabilities are waiting for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For scientific computing, C++ and Java are most often used. C++ is also one of the most popular languages in the world. With the help of the program code of this language, you can do various arithmetic operations. It can be used for modeling and calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists use various programming languages, the choice of which depends on the type of task and the preferences of the author. Historically, the first high-level programming language is Fortran, it has written many well-established libraries of mathematical statistics and libraries for solving differential equations, which is relevant for economics and biology, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has a simpler syntax, which is also suitable for programming mathematical calculations. Python is used for data processing in mathematics, physics, economics, biology, chemistry and is able to work with some other &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; languages: Fortran, C++, C#.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In turn, C# allows programming on the platform.NET, adapt the program to the common language runtime environment (CLR) and accelerate development in the framework of operational scientific sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The design of the report.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/report_fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 22:05:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/report_fixes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to GOST 7.32-2001, any research work must necessarily
contain the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;title page;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summary;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the main part;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOST also recommends including the following elements in the work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list of performers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regulatory references;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definitions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designations and abbreviations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list of sources used;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;applications.
If you are carrying out complex work performed in several stages, then you may
need to include part or all of the elements of the second list in the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The content of the main elements of the report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title page.The first list of work is formed according to a strict pattern, which is usually given in methodological manuals on your subject.It is not required to specify such elements as the name of the educational institution, the type of work and information about the performer, but also to arrange them in strict accordance with the standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract.The abstract is actually a summary of your entire report and contains a number of statistical information. In it, you need to specify the number of parts, pages of the work, illustrations, appendices, tables, used literary sources and appendices. Here is also a list of the keywords of the work and the text of the abstract itself.The latter implies the main elements of the work from the set goals to the results and recommendations for their implementation.In the practice of universities, the abstract is usually not included in the reports on laboratory work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction. In the introduction of a typical laboratory work, the goals of the study and the tasks that will help achieve the goals are usually prescribed. At the same time, there are works in which students become real pioneers.Have you ever experienced at least once a feeling of extreme curiosity and impatience during laboratory work? To feel that in just a couple of minutes you will find the answer to the question that
has no one ever found an answer yet? It is for such studies that a detailed introduction is written with proof of the relevance and novelty of the topic being studied.In order to really conduct research in this area, in which, as they say, no human foot has yet set foot, in the introduction you will need to give an assessment of the current state of the problem under consideration and justify the need for its solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main part. Since different universities and disciplines have their own subtleties of laboratory work, the content of the main part is described in detail in the relevant manuals. It is important that this section of the work reflects its essence, describes the methodology and results of the work done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main part prescribes the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objectives of the study;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tasks that will help you achieve your goals;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the progress of the work, which describes the actions performed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other sections provided by methodological materials on the discipline being studied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion.In this part of the work, you will need to draw conclusions from the results obtained during the laboratory work.To do this, evaluate how fully the tasks have been completed.In complex works, other elements may also be present, for example, recommendations for further application of the results of the work carried out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight markup languages.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 22:05:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/langs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed to easily and quickly add formatting to text data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum functions.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small set of supported tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The source text in such a language is read with the same ease as the finished document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Org-mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BB Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki markup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightweight languages for writing mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AsciiMath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
